Let me give this to you straight...
What kind of a man does that to his own son?
Elliot Hope is not a racist.
He's got family problems.
That's no excuse!
James, I...
I've got to go.
He called the wedding off...
Becky, we need to find him.
Thandie Abebe is incompetent.
I take full responsibility.
How many times must she screw up?
They make a lovely couple, don't they?
How long have you known?
Your father contacted our solicitor...
MY solicitor!
..Three weeks ago.
Hoped for a "clean break".
Positively surgical, don't you think?
A sharp knife and a steady hand and it's as if 30 years never existed.
Why didn't you tell me?
I do have a little pride left, darling.
Or I did.
It's all so undignified.
For all of us.
I'm going to talk to him.
No, please don't.
MOBILE PHONE BEEPS He's making a mistake.
Ah, I think, nowadays, I'm the mistake.
These thing happen, darling.
We just have to cope with them.
Don't talk to him.
No work?
No work, no cases, no admissions, no nothing.
Remind me, why did I agree to do a shift on Darwin?
Boredom is God's gift to the over-stimulated.
I advise you to revel in it.
Taking some of your own advice?
Background reading.
My racial awareness course.
Well, you can always make an excuse, I don't know, erm, someone needs a heart transplant, that kind of thing.
The wise man follows the path of least resistance.
Even if it's a waste of time?
Ah, you must be the early bird.
And what does that make you?
Latest minutes from the board.
Funding, new central initiatives.
All hot stuff.
Isn't it always?
Ahh...the awareness course.
It's today, isn't it?
Dr Miranda's a friend of mine.
I knew her at Johns Hopkins.
She's what you'd call a dynamic woman.
Oh, my favourite kind.
It's a shame we couldn't come to a more equitable arrangement.
Race is such a hot potato.
Heads have rolled because of it.
Big ones.
Guess who's knitting by the guillotine.
Do this for me and we can all get back to the important stuff.
Enjoy.
You don't think you could be overreacting?
Abra has done everything to undermine me.
Or there was a misunderstanding.
You can't afford bad blood in the department.
Last week, you were on my side.
I am.
But accusations, mud slinging - it never pays in the long run.
So you think I should apologise?
Maybe go down on my knees?
Would that make you happy?
All I'm suggesting is that you just meet Abra half way.
Swallow some of that pride.
Pride?
You never know who's watching.
OK.
I give up.
Where have you hidden them?
We've got a visitor.
Hmm.
Morning.
My day on the floor.
Once a month, whether I like it or not.
And we got lucky.
What are the chances?
Fair to middling, I'd say.
But will you like what you see?
Shall we?
To paraphrase someone or other, AAU is another country.
We do things differently here.
..
Still on Africa time, Dr Abebe?
As I was saying, this is our rapid assessment bay.
Obs, bloods, initial investigations all happen here.
15 minutes max, then it's decision time.
Anything to add, Mr Griffin?
Just that we're all behind you.
It's a great initiative.
A real team effort.
If you'll excuse me.
The punter, or do you prefer client?
What about patient?
Ooh.
He or she is then either referred on or transferred to one of our treatment areas, freeing the bay for the next one.
It's all pretty simple really.
It sounds it.
I can't wait to see it in action.
You will.
I mean, er... it's never usually this quiet.
Oh!
She said the Q word.
We never say the Q word.
Saying the Q word brings the world down on our heads.
The disco spin is the only known cure.
You did that, because I said quiet?
Oh, dear.
Though the power of the spin is strictly limited.
So please don't say it again.
For all our sakes.
Apparently, my ulcer also disapproves of divorce.
Joseph, I...
I understand how difficult this must be for you.
Believe me, and I assure you I would not have entered into it unless it was something extremely important to me.
Clearly.
If it's worth destroying our family for.
That was never my intention.
I suppose I just hoped you might understand.
Well, a dalliance, maybe.
But divorce?
My feelings have grown.
Slowly, but surely.
As have hers.
And if Jac is to step into Diane's shoes, then we all have to come to some agreement.
She's replacing Diane?
I thought the board decided not to appoint.
It was a change of heart.
I see.
And yet you still trust her motives?
Should I have any reason not to?
Yes, yes.
I remember those were my thoughts exactly.
What's she really doing here?
Checking up, snooping around, take your pick.
Question is, who tipped her off?
I'll give you one guess.
For once, I think we're in total agreement.
She seems all right, though.
For a CEO.
Oh, no.
Classic smiling death.
You don't see the knife till there's blood on the floor.
Don't you think that's just a little bit paranoid?
Oh, so you haven't heard the story?
She sacked her own father?
It was a family firm.
She'd been to business school, he asked for her help.
So darling Jayne restructured and decided Daddy was the weakest link.
Wow!
I think it was what they call a hostile takeover.
Our system works.
We've got nothing to worry about.
Maybe, but if I want to persuade her to support the night ops, we need to be cooking with gas today.
No slip ups, no mistakes, no surprises.
Treatment room.
Can't you just remove it?
Mr Prince has a six-inch stiletto in his praecordium.
It could be sitting in lung, pericardium, even myocardium...
Question is - how did it get there?
It was me.
I did it.
Oh, it's not her fault.
I asked her to.
To stab you?
No, no.
We, er...
We have an arrangement.
Geoff is my client.
He likes to be walked on.
It's my...my peccadillo.
But obviously not your wife's?
It happens.
Ask your husband.
Right, I'll call theatres.
We're going to need eight of O neg, an echo and five sets of crossed fingers.
So he's OK?
For a man with a shoe in his left ventricle, yes.
She can stay with me, right?
If that's what you want?
Yeah.
The hoards descend.
Shall we see your famous system at a stretch?
The Q word.
Today of all days, someone had to say the Q word.
It's groundless.
You did a perfectly good operation.
She just ended up with a minor wound infection.
The board will investigate, come to the same conclusions...
It's just a little unnerving.
Yeah, well, it's part and parcel.
If I had a penny for every time I'd had a complaint, I'd have...
How much?
Three pence.
Yes, that's not the best example.
But anyway, we'll deal with it.
So where are they off to this time, Margaret?
SHE PANTS Ibiza.
Ooh!
All right for some, eh?
Yeah!
Tut-tut.
Will you start the nebs and get a chest X-ray?
No problem.
One of your regulars?
Chronic Bronchitis.
You do realise an acute medical bed costs this hospital £430 a day?
We like to call it real life.
So if I could place her?
We would be forever in your debt.
Sounds like a challenge.
A bit like your other proposal.
Operating at night?
It's certainly original.
Yes, and necessary.
Have you seen the figures?
I have read it.
Doing it would mean staff operating after hours for no extra pay?
Yes, but...
Takes quite a boss to inspire that kind of team spirit.
Well... ..they're lucky they've got one, then.
Excuse me.
All I want is to be considered on my own merits.
And your determination to delay my morning list is duly noted.
Here, catch this, file it.
Oh, safe hands.
Welcome to the first 15.
But you do agree that we have to replace Diane?
Since when have the board taken any notice of my opinion?
I'll give you this back.
But you're backing the creation of a new consultant's post?
On clinical grounds if nothing else?
Listen, I have a very flat back swing and no time to groove in the changes my pro is insisting on.
Less time in theatre means more time on the range for yours truly.
But I'd want my choice of candidates.
Which means this thing goes out country wide - it's a fair fight.
And may the best man win.
Or woman.
Or indeed, woman.
I've no idea what you mean.
My father.
When you've got Diane's job, let him down gently.
You're just two different people, that sort of thing.
Or will you have the guts to tell the truth?
Which is?
That you're using him to further your career.
And as soon as you get what you want, you will move on and damn the consequences.
Or perhaps I love him.
Same way you loved me?
Kris Turner.
Got hit on the nose playing basketball.
He's tachy at 120.
Airway?
HE GROANS He's maintaining it, just.
Must be one hell of an elbow.
It's just a nosebleed.
So why isn't it stopping?
Because my brother's got haemophilia.
Ah!
I will be right with you.
Do you think an amateur with a flat back swing could ever win the British Open?
Do you think this... is an Open-winning action?
I would say almost certainly not, no.
Gimme two seconds.
I'm suppose I'm just nervous.
Afraid of a little competition?
Doesn't sound like you.
When something's this important.
The job means I can stay with you.
It's all in hand.
My hands.
I don't understand.
Ric Griffin needs a friend on the board.
I want you in that job.
Quid Pro Quo.
I can get this job on my own.
On my own merits.
I don't doubt it, but this is just a little insurance.
For us, our future.
You said so yourself.
I just want to make sure.
What about Clifford?
He won't accept a fait accompli.
If he finds out we're together...
Leave Daniel Clifford to me.
There is something else I need to tell you.
I've instructed my solicitor to take steps to... make our separation permanent.
You're getting a divorce?
Yes, I wanted to keep it quiet, but now Joseph knows, I thought you should hear it from me.
Please say something.
It is a big step.
But the right one.
Like this, we don't have to hide anything.
Unless you'd prefer it that way?
I'd understand.
In view of the potential conflict of interest as regards this job...
Oh, my God!
Some things are more important.
Well, you can say what you like about this place, it's never dull.
Er, sorry, you wanted to talk to me about something?
No.
KNOCK ON DOOR Come.
Thank you.
Curiouser and curiouser.
Yes?
Mr Hope?
Speaking.
It's DS Doyle.
DS Doyle.
We, er, have some news.
You've found him.
Thank God.
We need you to come down to the coroners office.
Stop that.
I wasn't expecting her to announce it to the world.
What's done is done.
I did ask you not to interfere.
Yes, and I'm sorry.
So you keep saying.
You did what you thought was right.
Still...
Now there's not much point in delaying things any longer.
Ah, speak of the devil...
Your father's clean break.
One signature?
There.
Gerald will be in touch with your man.
I take it it is a man?
Thank you for doing this...
I have to go.
We don't want any fuss, do we?
Oh, and I would be grateful if you'd keep any public humiliation to a minimum.
I really didn't want...this.
You've got what you wanted, Charles.
I was just wondering what you'd been telling Joseph?
I asked him to stay out of it.
Well, this doesn't involve him...
Of course it involves him!
What did you think was going to happen?
All change and then as you were?
If we can just remain civil.
Civil!
This is civil.
This is as civil as it's going to get between you and me.
I had hoped, after all these years, we could come to an amicable arrangement.
You know what really upsets me about all this?
It's all so disgustingly ordinary and grubby and...
You're not the man I thought you were.
I just hope you can live up to her expectations.
Whoa!
Board room's thataway.
I've got...
Something's happened, something important.
Yeah.
The course.
Path of least resistance, right?
The police called me.
I need to...
You have to tell them.
Let them know.
Here.
Car keys, car keys...
Just, just tell them.
Tell them what exactly?!
Pulse is still 130.
He's going into shock.
Give him two of O neg from the fridge.
Let's get the family out and the O neg in?
Come on, sweetheart.
Look, one, I'm not your sweetheart.
Two, I'm not going anywhere.
And three, if you give him O negative, you'll kill him.
My brother's got antibodies to Duffy A and B.
He needs Duffy negative.
Look...
OK.
So where is this blood...?
Duffy...
A and B negative.
It's a black thing.
Liverpool.
Let's get him a bed.
Assessment complete.
It's been accepted.
Three changes.
My telesurgery paper for the journal.
My father will be pleased.
I've worked for this.
All of it.
If I make consultant, I want it to be because of what I've done, what I've achieved.
I'm a good surgeon, Joseph.
I don't think that's ever been in doubt.
Can we put the past behind us?
Because you're a good surgeon?
No, because I don't want us to be like this - constantly undermining each other.
See, that's the point, isn't it?
It's all about you.
Your career.
Whatever you do, whoever you hurt, there's only one person who counts.
Listen to me.
I'm not the wicked stepmother.
There's no magic spell, no poison apple.
And if I'm in his bed tonight, it's because I want it and because he wants it.
Don't try and come between us.
Are you threatening me?
I'm telling you to grow up.
We hold off transfusion as long as we can.
Fill him up with colloids.
And if he doesn't stop bleeding?
A little faith, and a lot of factor eight.
Keep me informed?
Good job she spoke up for herself.
Tape.
Think that'll hold it?
In Uganda, we learned how to improvise.
In Holby, we do try not to.
It seems to me Dr Abebe's simply thinking on her feet.
Then in Kampala we trust?
Mr Prince, we will have to contact your next of kin.
This has to stay between you and me.
Patient confidentiality.
I know my rights.
I'm going to go.
Call your wife, Geoff.
No, Lalana.
Wait...
Hold him down.
She stays.
Let go.
You!
Sit...still.
Sit still, you...pathetic...little...worm!
Better.
Now you will do as I say.
What are the rules?
I do as you say, mistress.
Good.
I'm leaving.
Then this little slug will call the dreadful, overbearing and ungrateful Daily Mail-reading harridan he had the misfortune to marry.
Or he'll answer to Miss Lalana.
Mary Poppins.
Mary Poppins, please.
It's our safe word.
I want you, not her.
I want Mary Poppins.
Eugh!
Right.
Let's get that echocardiogram for Mary Poppins' friend here.
Jane... his wife has a right to know.
He has a right to confidentiality.
How would you feel?
We have to respect his wishes.
End of story.
And if he dies?
We'll make sure he doesn't, won't we?
Mr Hope?
Yes.
Is this your son's phone?
I don't know.
They all look so similar.
And he always upgrades, I keep telling him not to.
That's how they make their money you know?
Mr Hope...
Yes, er, Well, it looks familiar, but...
Take your time.
Your mother's on her way?
From Reading.
She's a drug rep.
She'll get here as soon as she can.
Have we got an Hb yet?
Something tells me you've done this before.
I've been coming here with him since I was four.
Clinics, admissions.
You pick up stuff.
I noticed.
So what are you studying?
Biology, Chemistry and Physics.
I want to go to med school, if I get the grades.
I can see you put the hours in.
If I get a chance.
He'll be fine, you know.
He always is.
Likes to give us all a scare.
I can watch him if you want to take a break?
Call you if he gets more tachy, right?
Right.
Maybe a text, a message may look familiar?
It's his.
I sent him this message.
In a moment, I'm going to take you inside.
The body will be covered.
When you're ready, my colleague will show you the face.
If you recognise the person, then all you have to do is tell me.
Would you like some time to prepare yourself?
And how would one do that, exactly?
It's cold.
Ready?
Elliot?
No.
This man is not James Hope?
This boy is not my son.
Diane Lloyd's replacement.
Any appointment will go through the usual channels.
But if word gets out that, er... there's already a local candidate who's got it in the bag, you'll find it very hard to attract serious competition.
That's what I've always found.
Everything will be above board.
You have my assurance on that.
I can ask for nothing more.
I must say...
Jac would complement you very well.
Beauty and the Beast?
I understand that, er... you're up for a merit award?
At the discretion of the board, of course.
Which you chair.
I have that honour.
And as you can imagine, the board tend to defer to me on these issues.
It's the birthday dilemma, isn't it?
What do you get the surgeon who has everything?
You have the fast car, the perfect house.
Suddenly money is no object.
Tell me, this trial you're involved in.
I believe there's some family connection there?
My brother's wife.
Of course.
You were very lucky to get funding for it.
What with research budgets getting ever tighter.
I assume you had commercial money?
Enough.
But of course, the future of the trial does depend on the board's discretion.
Long may it continue, eh?
Shall we see what becomes of the broken hearted?
Maybe I should tell Jill.
You know, everything.
What if something happens?
You're going to be fine.
Is that an order?
I thought we weren't playing that game any more?
There's the effusion.
We are into myocardium.
He needs to be in theatre.
Get these tapes to Connie.
She'll send as soon as she's reviewed them and you will be safe in her exquisitely manicured hands.
Ah!
Last but not least.
Dr Derezinski.
Don't try and pronounce it.
Call me Miranda.
Oh, and it's PhD, not MD.
You must be...
Dr Hope?
Actually...
It's not a question.
Eye colour?
Eye colour.
Let's go, Ellie.
Brown.
I should have known.
What do we think of that, group?
I don't get it.
You, Dr Hope, have just joined a minority.
Sit over there with the rest of your kind and maybe you'll learn something.
Bit over the top, isn't she?
Blue-eyed bitch.
Do you think he's going to die?
He's stable.
With the right operation, he's got every chance.
Which means he'll come back.
My regulars pay my rent.
Is that all he means to you?
Clients like Geoff - they get attached.
They imagine things, feelings which aren't there.
It's all part of the fantasy.
You did nothing to discourage him.
You can think what you like about me.
Believe me, I am.
I've said my piece.
You've both got your orders.
Now don't call her.
Music maestro please.
Colonoscopy playlist.
MUSIC STARTS Bat out of Hell, good choice.
You're not going to need that mask.
We're working in a world of you know what down here.
Shall we boldly go where no man has gone before?
And the doctor is in.
What concerns me is the clear conflict of interest here.
Now you know the situation....
I should raise merry hell?
Where would that get me?
Out of favour with the board and a senior colleague as an enemy.
Why fight City Hall?
It's the right thing to do.
Because Jac Naylor's using my father to influence the appointment committee.
Remind me something.
Did you dump her, or did she dump you?
Right, that was below the belt, wasn't it?
Apologies.
Everyone knows she dumped you.
My concern is for my father.
Then why don't you go talk to him?
They're biking the blood.
Three hours minimum.
His heart's failing.
We could risk it, hope he doesn't react to our blood.
And if he does?
So what now?
We push in the fluids, give the Factor Eight a chance.
Then wait.
Mark?
We wait.
OK.
I give up.
Where are you hiding them?
Open it.
Ah, Mr Bond.
This British ingenuity knows no bounds.
Well, enjoy it while you can.
It will be your last.
Do you expect me to smoke, Mr Durant?
No, Mr Bond.
I expect you to die.
She is using you just like she used me!
Well, how can you be so sure of that?
She was practically begging me not to support her.
"I want to get this job on my own merits."
Those were her exact words.
Does that surprise you?
No!
She says what she knows you want to hear.
I've done it often enough!
Making me the old fool?
Joseph.
I support her, like I support you.
You have never helped me!
Not once.
You had the Byrne name!
But she has talent, she has guts, she has drive.
You earned it, I was born with it.
If this is all about that stupid complaint, then forget it.
These things happen.
You'll be a great surgeon, boy.
I know it.
You love her?
Yes, I do.
And I love you.
And I do not believe the two positions are mutually exclusive.
Emotional distress, being abused, being singled out for a biological quirk that you can do nothing about.
This is how it feels every single day of your life.
Say it loud, baby, I'm brown and I'm proud.
Any other examples of discrimination?
I want to know how you felt.
Ms Elliot Hope.
Consultant cardiothoracic surgeon.
I can't do this...
Now, don't be modest, honey, and so young!
We are simply not worthy.
Even a high flier like you must have experienced some form of prejudice?
Erm, no, not really.
An attractive woman in a male-dominated culture?
Actually, I slept my way to the top.
Isn't that what you call positive discrimination?
You just volunteered for the next exercise.
They'll be landing about now.
Yeah, Ibiza's not all it's cracked up to be.
Just sand, sea and all the sex you can eat.
So who's the stuffed blouse?
Keeping her beady eye on me.
You look after your regulars, Mr Durant.
Most of 'em.
Can't you smoke any quicker?
I'm savouring it.
Even a decrepit old burden like me deserves a little guilty pleasure.
Burden?
Their loss is our gain.
What are you doing tonight?
Fancy a drink?
Long as it's a Pina Colada.
I'm very partial to Pina Coladas.
Then it's a date.
Hurry up.
Right, you're in luck.
They had the monthly clean this morning.
I'm joking...
All right, suit yourself.
All right, just stay here while I get help, OK?
What do you mean, cancelled?
I've been waiting for six months for my operation.
Emergency procedures take priority.
It's just a fact of life.
So why is it that you have time to operate on all those blue-eyed folks at the clinic?
They pay me.
Everyone knows blue-eyed people take priority.
Us browns just have to wait.
Well, maybe I don't want to wait any more.
Then it's the matter of my fee.
I've got no money.
Then you just have to wait.
Racist.
What did you call me?
I said, Ms Hope, that you are a racist.
That you're only refusing to operate on me because of the colour of my eyes.
You want to talk about prejudice?
I'll tell you about prejudice.
Try growing up a brown-eyed girl in a blue-eyed family.
Try working hard for something and having it snatched away just because your eyes don't fit.
So I changed, I changed and I started living a lie.
Because I had a dream, and this was the only way to make it come true.
Contact lenses.
See?
Brown.
Just like you.
So, what do you have to say to that?
You can sit down now.
All right, give it to me.
What happened?
He was collapsed in the bog.
It might be his stomach.
My father has a duodenal ulcer.
It may be bleeding.
Give me another one!
We get him scoped.
It's the only way to stop the bleeding.
Do you want me to have a go?
No.
I can manage.
Donna, how long?
A few minutes.
He was complaining about his ulcer.
I'll ring the endoscopy suite.
Right, FBC, U and E's, clotting factors and six units of crossmatch.
No, there's no ulcer.
Feel.
On the cusp, eh?
One Jimmy Choo between life and death.
This?
We see this kind of thing all the time.
Lucky you came on a quiet day.
Jill doesn't deserve this.
She's great, so solid, so real.
God knows what she's going to say.
Well, whatever it is, I think it will be better coming from you.
Women don't like surprises unless they come from Tiffany's.
What, you think I should talk to her?
You have no-one to blame but yourself.
I think he knows that, doctor.
No, no, she's right.
Why shouldn't she express an opinion?
I like strong women.
Jill is just the same.
God, she deserves better than me.
Better than this... constant deception.
Do you think she would understand?
If it came from you?
I don't know.
I can't, can I?
Even if I wanted to.
Have you been smoking?
It's called holistic medicine.
He's stable.
Just.
Theatres?
Still waiting.
His wife should be with him.
I've made my decision.
Of course, my opinion counts for nothing.
When you're a member of this team, when you've earned your place, then I'll listen to you.
Now, I'd appreciate it if you do as you are told.
I called.
The blood is still an hour away.
He hasn't got an hour.
And if we give him that blood?
It could be fatal.
And this hospital wouldn't have a leg to stand on in a court, right?
Right.
Give him the blood.
IV Piriton.
IV hydrocortisone.
We do all we can.
Geoff Prince, is he here?
I got a call, something to do with his heart?
Yeah, he's in the treatment room.
That's his partner over there.
She'll be able to fill you in.
Well?
7cm aneurysm.
We've got free fluid in the paracolic gutter.
And otherwise stable?
For now.
He's responding to the fluid bolus.
Good, then we heal with steel.
If he'd gone to endoscopy...
There's time for the touchy-feely stuff later.
Can I borrow your pen?
May I have the pleasure?
No.
We need to get this graft in fast, otherwise we're all gonna be tugging our forelocks to the new Lord B there, so I advise you to sign.
Joseph will perform this procedure.
Back in the real world, sign your life over to someone who can save it.
I'm competent and fully conscious.
My decision is final.
Joseph will operate.
You know I can't.
I completely concur.
An simple X here will do.
We don't have time for this.
If you don't want Daniel, then let me do it.
We have to operate now.
I need to talk to Joseph, alone.
Fine, come on.
Let's leave them to do the heart-to-heart while it's still beating.
Why?
Why me?
I'm in your debt.
I have... taken from you and given you nothing back in return.
That's not true.
Oh, yes, I have assumed the Byrne name is enough to make you into a great surgeon.
That is what you want, isn't it?
Yes, but...
Then I owe you this.
This chance to show to the world what Joseph Byrne is really capable of.
And risk your life?
High stakes, Joseph.
Do this, you can do anything.
Prove it to yourself.
I won't do it.
Won't, or can't?
Both.
Either you operate on me now or I'll die in this room.
It's you, you're the whore.
What have you done to him?
I'm leaving.
You're not going anywhere.
Mrs Prince...
Someone call security.
Quickly.
You'll talk to me!
Like you talk to him?
Why do you think he pays me?
It never occurs to you that there might be something missing.
A little something you can't provide.
What?
Sex for cash?
Cheap thrills from a £50 whore he picked up in Stokeville?
£50 wouldn't even buy him a disapproving look.
You want to see what Geoff spends his money on?
What he hasn't got the guts to tell you?
Here...take a look.
Jill!
You can't do this.
There's clear evidence of confusion.
I would have to disagree.
We'd be risking his life.
I concur.
But at this point I don't care if this operation is done by a monkey with a Stanley knife, somebody's got to stop the bleeding.
Fine, then let me do it.
No, you've been vetoed already.
You should have been more careful.
I think you wore him out.
Too much rumpy, now no pumpy.
Is that supposed to be funny?
Sorry, consultant humour.
But we'll both be doing that soon, have 'em rolling in the aisles.
As long as he lives.
Are you really this cold?
I prefer semi-detached.
I don't like being leant on.
Charlie just wants a knife he can trust.
You might not care about your registration but I do.
What if the GMC get involved?
Go call the GMC.
We'll be in there.
What was the wife doing here?
I'm asking myself the same question.
Let's move him to theatre.
Or if he stays here.
Well, let's tamponade him.
I need a Foley catheter.
Push it through and inflate the balloon.
It will buy us enough time to get him upstairs.
Have you done it before?
No.
You want to swap places?
Right.
Try it again.
Saline.
Forceps.
Well done, Dr Abebe.
Want to do your little dance?
Welcome to my world.
So how does it feel to be operating below stairs?
I have assisted on this procedure...
The thought of taking a knife to him...
MUSIC PLAYS Can we turn that off, please?
Kill the Tip.
All right, there's the sac.
Looks infra-renal.
One point to us.
See the rupture?
There.
And there.
Two points to God.
Let's try and even things up.
Feel for the neck.
Of course.
Blood pressure's dropping.
I can't see it.
Then feel.
Go down to the spine.
Got it?
I'm not sure.
Listen to me.
This is not Daddy dearest.
It's just a patient.
Just a lump of meat.
Do your job.
OK.
Right, I've found the renals.
The equaliser.
Ready for the second half?
Pulse is dropping.
No sign of a reaction.
It would have happened by now, right?
I'm checking his pulse.
Sac is open.
Suction.
And remove.
Still bleeding.
Lumbar artery.
Gets me every time.
2-0 silk?
So you must be disappointed.
I'm sorry?
Red, not blue.
Very neat work.
Sure you haven't done this before?
If one sticks to sound surgical principles...
One can remain utterly average.
It's Jac Naylor.
Checking on her investment?
Or am I just a hopeless cynic?
Tell her Lord Byrne's got the right man for the job.
The cross clamp's gone.
Suction please!
I can't...
More suction!
Get sued by the Byrne family?!
This is your mess.
But, I can't...
He's dying, please.
We all have to sometime.
Maybe I'll get his parking space.
I don't know what to do.
Then stop, think, choose, act.
I can't.
I...
He's right.
I can't do it.
Please.
Will you just...
Then he dies.
Think!
The wooden spoon.
Quickly, please.
And clamp.
Graft, please.
Yours, I think?
He's OK.
They're taking him up to theatre.
He's not a bad man.
He's a confused man.
I was confused once.
But not now?
I didn't realise that you were a...
Thank you.
Let me call you a cab.
I'll walk.
In those heels?
You'll have to wait a while for that inheritance.
Unless Ms Naylor gets there ahead of you.
Oh, and for the record, I choose my own team.
As long as the price is right?
Consultant training lesson one.
What you say and what you do are not the same thing.
Ms Naylor seems to have that knack.
One should lie to get ahead?
Maybe she does love your old man.
To me, in fact.
OK.
Better than God.
Back pats all round.
Leaking at the top end, swab!
It's not working.
So he gets the hugs, you get the attitude?
If you want to do this job, you need a little distance.
I want to be a good doctor.
You will be.
Come on.
This girl saved his life.
So?
Did we pass?
The incident should never have happened.
I intend to deal with it.
But who was the snake in the grass?
Sorry?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Someone reported us.
Anonymously perhaps.
So you thought you'd take a look.
I mean, stop me if I'm going wrong.
That was a brave decision.
We said the Q word and no-one died.
I found a bed for Mrs Jolly.
We are forever in your debt.
Hell hath no fury...
Altocalciphilia.
Hmm?
High heel fetish.
Ah.
Surprisingly common.
Me?
I'd have gladly walked all over him.
Thank you, sister.
For everything.
It was you.
You called her, didn't you?
I'm sorry.
No.
No!
You bloody stupid fool!
Incompetent...
Damn.
Why now?
I almost believed you there for a second.
Despite everything I know about you, you almost convinced me.
You were just looking after number one as usual.
I don't understand.
He had faith in me.
It's a shame you didn't.
Elliot?
I was just saying how much you contributed today, to Ms Greyson.
I spoke to no-one.
No-one.
Not Jayne Grayson and not Mrs Prince.
What is it with your accusations, your comments, your...
Prejudice?
Don't put words into my mouth.
Perfect timing.
Sit down.
Your fiancee was just explaining how her complaining to the CEO behind my back makes me a racist.
It's fascinating stuff.
It wasn't her.
Oh, come on Ric, loyalty is an admirable quality, but...
She didn't talk to Jayne Grayson.
I did.
It's my fault.
I got carried away.
Did you ask her to cover for you?
He asked me to explain.
I didn't.
I understand there were extenuating circumstances.
You'll re-take the course next week.
I'll arrange it with Miranda.
You, Dr Young, will face disciplinary proceedings.
No, she won't...
This is not negotiable.
It wasn't her fault.
I disagree.
Dr Young has no excuse.
This is not a game we're playing here.
I have to address this complaint and be seen to address it.
I'm sorry.
Then I'll resign.
No, Elliot.
I won't accept it.
There are two more parents out there right now, waiting, worrying, desperate for news.
Soon they'll get a phone call, just like I did.
Probably at some very inconvenient time.
They're going to go down, and have to look into the eyes of that dead boy, and say yes, that's our son.
And then their lives will be over.
I understand.
You have my sympathy.
But I cannot condone what Dr Young has done.
Then I refuse to take the course, at St James' or wherever.
Then you leave me no choice.
Both of you will have to face the board.
I'm genuinely sorry it has come to this.
Well, we did it.
The Q word.
Still, I don't think the CEO is exactly my best friend.
Actually, my best friend isn't even my best friend any more.
Shall we tell Mrs Jolly the good news?
Margaret.
Oh, no!
Need some help here, please!
BUZZER SOUNDS I need a crash trolley, please!
It wasn't your fault, Joseph.
Every operation, there are risks.
Whatever we do.
You know that.
You have to listen.
How severe, please?
With the right rehab, there's every chance of a full recovery.
I want you to concentrate.
Squeeze as hard as you can.
Try again.
Again, please.
It's fine.
No.
Not like this.
You made your bed.
Still want to lie in it?
Pina Colada.
Quiet in here tonight.
Sorry mate, no smoking.
Arrest me.
Sorry.
Want to make that two.
Thought you gave that up?
I did.
This isn't mine.
Let me guess.
I shouldn't be too judgemental, you're your own man.
Exactly.
But angrier.
I stand by what I did.
Thandie deserves every chance.
And not just because of me.
She saved your patient.
It's true.
Your behaviour towards her was unacceptable.
I had no choice but to let Jayne Greyson see for herself.
You'll like this one.
This prostitute picks up a client and as they're doing it, she can't help noticing that he's whispering.
She can never quite hear what he's saying, but he keeps whispering all the time, whisper, whisper, whisper.
And eventually she says, "Look, "if you're going to whisper, "at least whisper in my ear."
So he leans forward, and whispers in her ear.
And d'you know what he's saying?
(I've only got a fiver. )
We all get taken for a ride sometime.
Do things we wouldn't normally do.
Cover for people.
Make phone calls to CEOs.
The trick is to see it before it's too late.
I'm getting married.
That's my point.
Enjoy your drink.
Cheers.
Bangkok?!
He phoned you from Bangkok?
Yes, yes.
Thank you.
Thank you, Becky.
Yes, OK.
Bye.